# **ESMA ERDEM**

Bangor, ME | 207-412-8936 | esmaerdem94@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

Highly motivated Software Engineer with entry-level experience in software development, Python and Javascript. Equipped with proven problem-solving and analytical thinking skills gained through Astronautical Engineering with High Honors Degree and a track record of success in team leadership and effective communication in my previous role as a sales manager. Excited to combine my technical skills and business acumen to drive impactful results and grow with the company.

### **SKILLS**

Web Development, JavaScript, AJAX, Git, SQL, PostgreSQL, Python, Flask, Node.js, Express, Jasmine, Jest

#### **PROJECTS**

## Wicked Acadia Wicked Acadia Live GitHub Repo

*Apr 2023 – May 2023* 

- Developed a comprehensive platform to assist nature enthusiasts in planning visits to Acadia National Park. Utilized a tech stack including Python, Flask, JavaScript, Postgres, and Jinja templates.
- Integrated user-friendly features include user sign-up, secure login, and favorites/bookmarks functionality.
- Implemented advanced security practices, including sensitive information hashing and password reset via email.
- Designed an efficient Restful API to interface between the front-end and database, caching external API data storage.
- Employed Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) techniques to architect and establish relational database models.
- Embraced object oriented programming principles to enhance code reusability and maintainability.
- Ensured the creation of extensive documentation and rigorous unit tests, including Flask integration tests, to achieve bug-free and maintainable code.

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

Springboard | Online

Current

Software Engineering Certification

- Key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Included 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of in-depth portfolio projects.
- Honed skills in Data Structures, and Algorithms, Web Development, JavaScript, AJAX, Git, SQL, PostgreSQL, Python, Flask, Node.js, Express.

# Turkish Aeronautical Association University | Ankara, Turkiye

July 2017

BS Astronautical Engineering, 3.29

- Relevant Coursework: Algorithmic Computer Programming, Linear Algebra, Computational Methods, Control Systems, Space Environment, Attitude Determination and Control
- Acquired advanced algorithmic and computational skills through rigorous coursework and an immersive internship experience. Self-taught Matlab and expertly applied these skills to successfully complete internship projects and subsequent coursework.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Student, Springboard Software Engineering | Remote

Jan 2023 - Current

- Gaining a deep understanding of software development, with a focus on web application architecture and functionality.
- Applying clean and concise programming practices, prioritizing collaborative code readability.
- Emphasizing documentation and rigorous testing for bug-free, maintainable code.
- Implementing diverse hands-on projects, including data structures and web applications.
- Proficiently managing relational databases through SQL and enhancing functionality with API integration.

Sales Manager, Cool As A Moose | Provincetown, MA

Jan 2019 - Sept 2022

- Achieved 70% revenue growth in the first year through effective customer service and strategic planning.
- Conducted regular health checks on the point-of-sale system and analyzed inventory data using retail star software.
- Developed and executed successful marketing campaigns, increasing brand visibility and community engagement.
- Coached and trained new hires across multiple locations on operations, customer service, and leadership.